- Hey, guys. - Hey.
- 嗨，大家 - 嗨！
Honey, I got us that room at the Woodford Inn this weekend.
亲爱的，这周末我有订到那个六福饭店
That place in Vermont? You can take a hint.
就是在佛蒙特的? 我的暗示果然有用!!
You can't go away this weekend. It's Emma's birthday.
你们这周未不能外出啊 那天是艾玛生日
We're having a party.
会有一个派对
Can't you have the party when we get back?
能不能等我们回来再举办呢?
No. It won't be her real birthday.
那就会很怪，等于不是她真正的生日
Gee, if only she were 1 and had no idea what the hell a birthday was.
喔，更何况她才一岁 也不知道生日到底是什么
Come on, you guys, this is really important to us.
嘿，这对我们很重要呢
Sorry, but Chandler and I could really use a weekend away..
喔，很抱歉，我和钱德 希望一起度过假日
- you know, to reconnect, emotionally. - There's this thing I really want us to do.
- 我们想沟通沟通，心理上的 - 我们从以前就很想做这件事
I read about it in Maxim.
我在 Maxim 杂志看到的
Well, can't you just go to Vermont the next day?
你们可以选择其他日子吧?
Yeah, we want everyone to be there.
我们非常希望大家都能来...
As much as I hate to delay your doing weird sex stuff to my little sister.
跟我非常讨厌你对我妹做 那奇怪的“性”事，一样多
And, I mean, you know, you guys, this is a big deal.
听著，这是一件大事呢
How can we have her first birthday party without her aunt and her uncle?
他不能度过他的一岁生日 如果没有他阿姨和叔叔陪他
I promise I won't do any magic.
我保证我绝对不会表演魔术的
All right, we'll stay. We can just drive up after the party.
好的，我们会留下来 还是可以赶过去
Fine. But if we end up not doing this Maxim thing because of this party..
如果派对的事情害 我们没做杂志上的事情--
Believe me, that is not why we won't be doing that.
那不是理由，好不好?
One With The Cake
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
You know, Phoebe, when I was little, on my birthday..
你知道吗，菲比 小的时候... 在我的生日那天...
my daddy would hide a present in every room of the house.
我爸会在家里每个房间藏礼物
And then he would draw a treasure map to help me find them all.
然后会给我们“宝藏地图” 叫我们自己找
I love family traditions like that.
喔，我喜欢这种家庭习俗
When Ursula and I were kids, on our birthday..
但小时候，在我生日 我继父...
our stepdad would sell his blood to buy us food.
...会去卖他的血 来买吃的
- Hey, guys. - Hi.
- 嗨，大家 - 嗨
- I brought the camera for Emma's video. - Oh, good!
- 我带了摄像机，来录艾玛的派对 - 喔，好呢
We had this idea to make a birthday video for Emma..
我们想要录艾玛的派对
- and we'll give it to her when she's 18. - Oh, cool.
- 当她十八岁时，再拿给他看 - 喔，酷
- Wow, it's like a time capsule. - Yeah.
- 就像一个“时空胶囊” - 是啊
Oh, just think, she's gonna be watching that video on a TV..
想象一下，到时 她就会在一个当前未发明
that hasn't even been invented yet..
的电视机上来看这个影带
with friends who, right now, are just, like, babies.
和朋友， 当前跟她一样还是个婴儿， 一起看
And they'll be living in a floating city that the humans built..
然后，我们住在一个浮起来的城市...
to escape the ant people.
...为了逃避蚂蚁人
That's the hope.
希望是如此!!
- So is Emma awake yet? - No, it's still naptime.
- 所以，艾玛起来了吗? - 没有，现在午睡时间
- But she'll be up soon. - Where's Joey?
- 不过，马上他就会醒了 - 乔伊在哪里呢?
I said, it's still naptime.
我说过了，现在是午睡时间
- Hey, there's Uncle Joey. - Hey.
- 嗨，来看看乔伊叔叔吧 - 嘿！
Hey, say something to Emma on her 18th birthday.
说句话，给十八岁生日的艾玛吧
- Eighteen, huh? - Joey, no!
- 十八岁，哈? - 嘿，乔伊，不要--
What? What? It's for her hot friends.
怎么啦，怎么啦 ? 是要给艾玛很辣的朋友
When they see this, you'll be 52.
当他看到这个，你已经是五十二岁了
And starting to think about settling down.
就是我开始稳定下来的时候呢
Joey, will you please set this up for people to put Emma's presents on?
乔伊，可以帮我打开吗? 这样就可以放艾玛的礼物
Love to. Yeah.
喔，非常愿意呢
- We were supposed to bring presents? - Yeah. I wrote Emma a song.
- 我们要给他礼物吗? - 是啊。我写了一首歌给艾玛
Oh, yeah. How was I supposed to know?
那，我怎么会知道呢?
- Joey, it's a birthday party. - Yeah, but for a 1-year-old.
- 这是一个生日派对呢 -是啊，但她仅一岁而已
What's the point? The other day she laughed for an hour at a cup.
重点在哪里? 那天她对著杯子大笑一个多小时
Just a cup with a picture of Elmo on it, dressed as a farmer.
只是一个普通杯子 上面有阿母的农夫图案
And he's standing next to this cow, and the cow says, "El-moo."
阿母站在牛旁边 牛说了：阿母-母-母-母
Man, that's a funny cup.
真是好笑的杯子
- Hey. - Hey.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Where's the birthday girl? - Oh, she's still napping.
- 生日的女主角呢? - 她还在睡觉呢
She was probably up all night excited about the party she knows is happening.
喔，当然，他昨晚知道要办一个派对... ...就太兴奋了，睡不着
I know you guys really want to get to Vermont, and this isn't a big deal to you.
我知道，你们很想去佛蒙特 对你们也是一件大事
But it really is to us, okay? Emma will never have a first birthday again.
但这对我们也是一件大事，好吗? 艾玛不会再有第二次的一周岁生日
You're right. We're sorry.
好的，你对，我们很抱歉
Let's wake up Emma and get the fun time started!
那把艾玛叫醒，开始派对吧!!
She didn't sleep well last night, so we can't wake her.
她昨晚睡不好所以我们不能叫醒她
Are you frigging kidding me, Greene?
你是不是在跟我开玩笑啊， 姓格林的!!
- Hi! - Hey!
- 嗨 - 嗨
- I'm so glad you came. - I can't believe Emma's already 1.
- 很高兴你来了 - 真不敢相信，艾玛已经一岁了
I remember your first birthday.
我还记得你的一岁生日
Ross was jealous of all the attention we were giving you.
罗斯很羡慕我们给你的一切
He pulled on his testicles so hard..
他很用力的去拉他的蛋蛋
we had to take him to the emergency room.
所以我们要带他去看急诊
There's something you didn't know about your dad.
有些关于你爸爸的事情你还不知道
Hey, Mr. and Mrs. Geller. Let me help you with that.
嗨，盖勒先生和太太 我帮你放下来吧
- Thank you. - Oh, man, this is great, huh?
- 谢谢 - 见到你们真好
The three of us together again. You know what would be fun?
我们三个又聚在一起 你知道更有趣的事吗?
If we gave this present to Emma from all of us.
就当做这礼物是我们三个人一起送给艾玛的，怎样?
Which one are you?
你是哪一位啊?
- I can't believe Emma's still asleep. - I know. What are we gonna do?
- 真不敢相信，艾玛还在睡 - 我知道，但没辙儿啊
I've got a plan. I've got a plan.
我有计划，一个好计划
I'm going to ram this platter really hard into your ribs.
我会把这个铁盘 很用力的砸到你身上
You're gonna scream out, and that'll wake her up.
那你会痛的哇哇大叫 这样会吵醒她，对不对?
I'm not going to Vermont with this Monica.
我不会和这种莫妮卡去佛蒙特的
Hey, Phoebe? You know what?
嗨，菲比，你知道吗?
I was thinking since you wrote a song..
即然你写了歌给艾玛
maybe I could do something for Emma using my talents.
那我也可以给艾玛表演我的才艺?
So you're gonna hit on her?
所以，你要去泡艾玛，是不是?
No, no, no. My talents as an actor.
不是，不是啦 我的才艺是演戏
You know, I could, like, maybe..
我可能，可以--
I could do a dramatic reading of one of her books.
给她边读本书边演出来
Or you could stick a fork in an apple.
或是，你可以把一个叉子叉在苹果上?
- Hey, I think Emma might like it. - Oh, Emma might like what?
- 嘿，我想艾玛会喜欢呢! -喔，艾玛会喜欢什么?
- My present. - What did you get her?
- 我的礼物! -你要给她什么?
- We prepared performances. - Separate performances.
- 实际上，我们正准备一个表演 - 分开的的表演呢
But equally real.
但是差不多
That sounds like fun.
喔，听起来好好玩了
People are getting a little antsy waiting for Emma to wake up from her nap.
你知道吗？ 因为大家有点不耐烦要等艾玛起来...
So would you mind performing them once now?
...所以，你们可以现在表演一个吗?
- Sure, yeah! - Okay.
- 当然可以 - 好--好，那好吧
Okay. All right. Everybody, let's get this party started.
大家听著，我们开始吧
Joey and Phoebe are gonna perform a little something for us.
乔伊和菲比要表演给大家看呢
Oh, great.
喔，太好了
Aren't you gonna be embarrassed having nothing prepared?
那你会不会觉丢脸 还没准备就上去表演呢?
I do it every week with three cameras pointed at me and a whole crew waiting.
嘿，我每个礼拜都这样呢，还加上 三个摄像机和所有剧组人员等著我
So, Joey, what are you gonna do for us?
那，乔伊，你要表演什么呢?
I will be doing a dramatic reading of one of Emma's books.
我会边读艾玛的书边演出来
Oh, okay. Which one?
哇，好耶，哪一本?
Well, it's one of her favorites.
哇，她收藏的其中一个
"Riding the Storm Out: Coping With Postpartum Depression."
从暴风雨中脱险： 对抗产后的抑郁症 咿--咿--咿
Love You Forever.
始终爱你
"Love You Forever, by Robert Munsch. Published by Firefly Books. Printed..
始终爱你，作者：罗柏.曼 萤火虫出版社出版
in Mexico.
墨西哥印刷
A mother held her new baby and very slowly rocked him..
一个母亲抱起他的婴儿 慢慢的，往前摇，往后摇
back and forth, back and forth, back and forth.
往前摇，往后摇... 往前摇，往后摇...
And while she held him, she sang, 'I'll love you forever.
当母亲抱着时，他唱了： 我会始终爱你
I'll like you for always. As long as I'm living..
我会一直喜欢你 只要我还活着
my baby you'll be.'"
你就是我的孩子
"And while he rocked her, he sang:
当母亲抱着时，他唱了：
'I'll love you forever. I'll like you for always.
我会始终爱你，我会一直喜欢你
As long as I'm living..
只要我还活着
my baby you'll be.'"
你就是我的孩子
Oh, wow!
哇！
That was amazing.
哇，真的太棒了
Thank you so much for that gift.
真的非常感谢你的礼物
I was not ready for this today.
今天我心理没有这个准备呢
- Amazing. Amazing. - Phoebe, I'm sorry.
- 太棒了，太棒了 -喔，菲比，抱歉
- Phoebe has prepared something as well. - That's right.
- 菲比也要表演给大家看 - 没错，
I prepared a song for Emma, from my heart to hers.
我准备了一首歌给艾玛 直接从我心里到她心里
For there's no greater gift than the gift of music.
没有比音乐更好的礼物了
Emma Your name poses a dilemma
“艾玛” “你的名字给我一个困境”
'Cause not much else rhymes with "Emma"
“和你名字押韵的少极了”
Maybe the actor Richard Crenna He played the commanding officer in Rambo
“也许仅有演员理查德・克里纳” “他是演蓝波的长官”
Happy birthday, Emma
“生日快乐，艾玛”
Is that it?
就这样?
No, of course not.
不，当然不是，还有--
No, I've also, you know, prepared a reading.
其他的-- 我也要朗读
"Sex and the Single Mother."
性爱和单身母亲
- "Finding your G-spot." - Oh, no, no, no!
- 查找性感带的方法 - 不要啊
Hello, Emma. Happy 18th birthday.
嗨艾玛, 祝你十八岁生日快乐
Right now, that seems so far away,17 years.
如果从现在算起，还有十七年之久呢
Yes. You'll be all grown up by then, and we'll be..
到时候你已经长大了，而到时候我们---
Well, your grandfather and I might not be here.
你公公和我都不在了
That's true. This message could be coming to you..
没错，这信息
from beyond the grave, Emma.
会是来自我们的坟墓里
- After all, my parents died very young. - And my cholesterol's off the charts.
- 还有，我父母亲很年轻就过世了 - 我的胆固醇还过高呢
Remember, Emma, heart disease kills women too.
艾玛，请记得 女生也会因心脏病而死
Okay, cut! Great. Great. That was just..
好了，好了，这样就够了
- Yeah. - Oh, good.
- 噢！ - 哦，好的！
Ross, don't forget to get a shot of Emma's cake.
罗斯，别忘了要拍蛋糕
- It's in a box in the fridge. - Okay, sure.
- 在冰箱的盒子里 - 好的，没问题
You're gonna love this cake. I got it from a bakery in New Jersey, Carino's.
喔，你会喜欢这蛋糕 我从新泽西州的面包店买来的，加理诺面包店
Oh, my God, that place has the creamiest frosting!
喔，他们有全世界最好吃的奶油
I used to hitchhike there when I was a kid.
我小时候喜欢搭便车去那里
Well, anyway, they make these great novelty cakes..
无论如何，他们做了很多种口味
in all different shapes. And if you give them a photo, they'll copy it in icing.
也很多种造型，如果你自己准备照片 他们还会放到蛋糕上
- Did you do a picture of Emma? - Yes. On a cake shaped like a bunny.
-那你一定放艾玛的照片喽 -当然，在一个兔子形的蛋糕
Rach? Does this bakery by any chance also bake..
瑞秋，这家店是不是刚好
erotic cakes?
也卖色情蛋糕?
Say, for bachelorette parties?
上面写：给单身派对使用
Ross, what are you talking..? Oh, my God!
你在讲什么啊? 喔，我的天啊。
They put my baby's face on a penis!
他们还把 我女儿的脸放在“小弟弟”上
Now it's a party!
这才像派对嘛
Wait, you guys, this isn't funny.
喔，如果真有那么好笑的话
If I wanted this cake to be a disaster, I would have baked it myself!
我也可以自己做这种形状的啊
Is it okay that I still think it looks delicious?
啊，没事，我还是认为很好吃
- Jack, look at this. - I know what you're thinking, Judy.
-杰克，你看看 -我知道你在想什么
The resemblance is uncanny.
其相似程度非常惊人
I am this close to tugging on my testicles again.
我也差点再度拉我的蛋蛋
Ironically, that was the Maxim thing.
讽刺的是, 那和Maxim杂志一样.
No, no, this is not what I ordered, okay?
不是，不是，这不是我要订的
I went all the way to New Jersey so that I could have the perfect cake..
我特地去新泽西州 只为了我女儿有完美的生日蛋糕
for my daughter's birthday. And I need a bunny cake right now!
还有，我需要兔子蛋糕。现在!!
Ask them if it would be faster if we cut the baby's face off the penis..
如果要快点的话，我们 可以从“小弟弟”上取出你的照片，
so we could put it on the bunny.
再贴到兔子蛋糕上
That is a weird sentence.
好像不是很适当
Oh, believe you me, I am going to bring this cake back.
我会把蛋糕换回去
I don't even want it in my home. Don't touch it!
甚至我不想有这种蛋糕在我家 乔伊，不要碰
I'm so confused!
我很疑惑啊!!!
Yes, I still want my daughter's picture, but on a bunny cake!
是的，我还是要我女儿照片 但是在兔子形状的蛋糕上
Yellow cake, chocolate frosting with nuts!
黄色蛋糕，有奶油和花生!!!
To be fair, this one does have nuts.
说实在的，这上面没有花生
Mon, it was nice of you to loan Rachel your car..
嗨，莫妮卡，你真好把车借给瑞秋
- so she could get the cake. - It was nice of her to pull my hair..
-为了她可以换蛋糕 -因为她一直拉我头发
till I dropped the key.
至到我给她钥匙
Well, while we're waiting, you could tape your message to Emma..
你知道吗，即然闲著 就先录一段给艾玛的...
for her 18th birthday, huh? Okay?
十八岁生日 好不好?
Hi, Emma. It's the year 2020.
嗨，艾玛，现在是 2020 年
Are you still enjoying your nap?
你还在享受你的睡眠吗?
We're Aunt Monica and Uncle Chandler, by the way.
我们是莫妮卡和钱德
You may not recognize us..
你可能不认识我们
because we haven't spoken to your parents in 17 years.
因为我们已经十七年了 没有和你父母亲讲话
We used to be married.
我们本来已结婚
But then we missed a weekend away together, and things kind of unraveled..
但我们搞砸了 我们的一个周末，造成我们分开
because of you.
就是因为你!!!
- Happy birthday. - Thanks. Another good one.
-生日快乐!! -谢谢. 又一个有趣的胡扯
I can't believe I taped over my Big Brother audition for this.
我不能相信我竟然录了这些.
Ross, Rachel promised it would be over by now.
罗斯, 瑞秋答应过这时候应该结束了
We seriously have to go if we want to get to Vermont.
我们如果要去佛蒙特现在该出发了
- The last train leaves in a half-hour. - And I have a massage client soon.
-我问过了，最后班次在半小时后 -你知道吗，我有要按摩的客户
You guys, just, please, a little bit longer.
嘿，大家，忍耐一下
I promise, Rachel will be back with the cake any minute.
瑞秋随时会带着蛋糕回来
Monica, remember the frosting, huh?
莫妮卡，记得该店的奶油味道吗?
All right, five more minutes.
好，我再等五分钟
Hello?
喂?
Oh, no, what happened?
发生什么事?
Okay, okay, where are you?
好的，好的，你在哪里?
Okay, I'll be right there.
我会过去的
Was that Emma? Is she up?
那是不是艾玛? 她起来了吗?
Rachel got pulled over for speeding.
瑞秋因为超速被拦下来
She forgot her license. I have to bring it to her.
她忘了带车照，我得送过去
- If you're leaving, I'm definitely going. - Wait, if anybody gets to go, it's us!
-如果你要走，那我也得走 -等一下，如果有人要走那就是我们
We've been complaining the longest!
是我们抱怨最久的
No, wait, you guys. No, you can't leave.
等等，你们不能离开
Rachel already feels bad that the cake's messed up.
蛋糕的事已让瑞秋很烦
How do you think she'll feel when she comes back and you're gone?
如果回来时发现大家不在 那她会怎么觉得?
I don't know. You'll tell us on Monday.
我不知道，你礼拜一再告诉我吧
Joey, you're in charge, okay? You make sure nobody leaves.
乔伊，你负责这里，要确认没有人离开
Got it!
了解
Hey! Where do you think you're going?
嘿嘿嘿，你要去哪?
To the bathroom.
去洗手间啊
Well, the rest of you get comfortable, because we are gonna be here for a..
即然大家会待一段时间 请当做自己家里--
- Wait, there's a window in there. - No! He's not getting away that easy!
-等等，洗手间里有个窗户... -不要让他逃走
What are you doing? Get the hell out of here!
喂，你们干什么啊!! 快滚出去啊!!
Well, that one did not have Emma's face on it.
那个“小弟弟”上没有艾玛的照片
- No, it did not. - No.
-是，当然没有 - 对。
Well, we'd better get going. It's late.
已经很晚了，我们真的要走了
Jack can't drive at night anymore. He has trouble staying in his lane.
杰克不能在晚上开车了
Last winter I went up on a church lawn and drove right through a manger scene.
去年冬天，我开车经过教堂的草地 然后撞上马的食槽
The papers thought it was a hate crime.
报纸误以为那是一个报仇计划
- Anyway, it was lovely seeing you. - Okay.
-无论如何，很高兴可以见到你们 -好的
- Bye. Bye, dear. - Nighty-night.
-再见 -晚安
- Nighty-night. - Bye.
-晚安 - 再见.
- How could you just let them leave? - Hey, hey, hey.
-乔伊，你怎么可以让他们离开? -嘿嘿
I'm not gonna mess with Jack. He's a great man. He fought for our country.
我不会和杰克过不去的 他是一个好人，为国家而战
No, he didn't. He pretended to be a Quaker to get out of Korea.
他才没有呢，他装成贵格会教徒 才可以逃离韩国
Well, that's it. He's the last one to go. I'm locking you guys in.
够了，他是最后一个离开的 我把门锁上了
You do know I can just turn them the other way around, right?
你知道那个锁是 可以从这里面打开的
Oh, I forgot you used to live here.
喔，我忘了你以前住过这里
- Hello? - Joey, it's Estelle.
-喂 -乔伊，我是你的经纪人 Estelle
- Hey. - So how'd your audition go today?
-嗨，你好 -你今天的试镜如何?
- What audition? - The one I told you about last week.
-什么试镜? -上礼拜我和你说过的啊?
What? You never said anything about an audition.
什么？你根本没有说过任何试镜!
Let me start over. I just got a call about an audition.
那我从头说起，我刚接到你的试镜通知
I think you can still make it.
你现在去还来得及
It's down at the Astor Theater, and you need to have a monologue prepared.
就在Aster戏院，还要自己带独白
A monologue? I don't have a..
独白? 我没有呢--
I got it.
喔，有了...
So I'm gonna take off.
那我要走了
- What? - No, wait! You don't get to leave.
-什么？ - 不，等等，你不能离开
I've got a massage client waiting outside my door any minute.
我有按摩客户等在我家门外呢
And we paid for a room that we're supposed to be in right now!
我们已经付钱给一个 我们现在应该住在里面的房间
Well, okay, now..
好好
only one of us has to stay with Emma.
只要有一个人照顾艾玛就行了
Okay, and as the person who realized that, I get to go.
因为是我刚发现这点的 所以我可以走了
No, no, no. No. No.
不行，不行
Let's figure out a fair way to decide who's staying.
那我们想一个较公平的 方法来决定谁要留下来
Oh, I got it.
喔，有了。
Okay, everyone pick a number from one to 10, all right?
大家选择一到十的数字
Whoever gets the highest number gets to go first.
谁选到最大的数字可以先走
- Okay,10. - Okay, Monica picks 10. I call nine.
-好喔，我选“十” -那我选“九”
Anyone else?
还有其他的吗?
- No, let's just draw straws. - Okay.
-大家来抽签吧?	 - 好。
Or we could flip a coin and multiply the answer..
或是可以用硬币--
- I'm begging you to stop. - Right.
-拜托你，不要讲话了 - 好。.
Okay, how about this? We got wind-up toys for Emma.
这样好啦，我们从艾玛的 生日礼物选一个发条玩具
We can make them race, and whoever comes in last stays.
拿来赛跑 跑最后的就要留下来
Yeah, let's do that!
好吧，就这样
That sounds more fun than the thing we were gonna do in Vermont!
这好像和佛蒙特的事情比起来好玩多了!
- Okay, everybody, pick your toys! - Okay. I want the dolphin!
- 好，各位，开始选玩具吧。 -我要用那个海豚!!
- That's a bear! - I'm too excited!
-菲比，那是一只熊 -抱歉，我太兴奋了!!
Phoebe, you get the bear. Joey, you get the robot.
菲比，你用这只熊 乔伊，你用机器人
- Oh, yeah. - And Chandler and I get the dog.
-哦，好的。 -钱德和我就用这只狗吧
And the race is going to go from here to here.
比赛就要开始了... 从这里，到这里
Now, the one who comes in last stays!
谁最后一名的，要留下来!!
Okay, ladies and gentlemen, wind your toys.
各位先生及女士，卷好你的发条
- Okay. On your mark, get set, go! - Go! Go!
-准备了吗?预备，开始！ -快，快!!
Come on, robot!
不要停!机器人！
What are you barking at?
你在干什么啊?!!?
Well, how is that gonna help?
那个动作有什么作用吗!?!?
I bought you! How did I forget that that's all you do?
我买了你! 我竟忘了你只会这个动作?
Way to go, robot!
好样的, 机器人!
Good job, Alan.
干的好，熊熊
- Hey, good race, you guys. - Yeah, see you later.
-真是一个好比赛 -是啊，那就再见喽
No. No, no. Wait.
不，不，你们等一下
We didn't lose.
我们没有输呢
The rules clearly stated that the last one to cross the finish line was the loser.
规定是说，最后跑到终点才是输家
Well, our dog never crossed the finish line. So technically..
那我们的狗，没有跑到终点，所以--
They left.
他们已经走了!
There isn't time to go to the bakery. We're gonna come home.
你知道吗? 根本没时间去面包店 所以我们现在回家了
Everybody left?
大家已经走了?
All right. Well, just tell Emma that we'll be there as soon as we can. Bye.
好喔，告诉艾玛 我们会尽快回家，再见
- Rachel! - Oh, God, sorry!
-瑞秋!!! -喔，天啊，抱歉
I can't believe they gave you a ticket. You're such a good driver.
真不敢相信，他们给了你一个罚单 你真是一个好驾驶人
- Emma's awake. - Yeah?
-艾玛起来了 -是喔?
I can't believe this.
真不敢相信
This is her first birthday, she's awake, we're not even there.
在她的一岁生日 她醒来时，我们不在
Everybody left. We still have this stupid obscene cake.
大家也已经走了 还加上这个烂蛋糕!!!
Hey, maybe I can fix that. You know, try to turn it into something else.
嘿，也许我可以弄好这蛋糕 试试看，改成别的形状嘛
Oh, don't even bother.
已经无所谓了
We've already ruined her first birthday.
我们已经毁了她的第一个生日
And do you know how important these early experiences are, Ross? Very!
你不知道这些早期的经验 对她有多重要吗，罗斯?非常重要
According to the back cover of that book that you gave me.
依照你给我的那本书背面
Rach, she's not gonna remember this.
瑞秋，她不会记得这些
I guess.
也许吧
Oh, I just had such an idea of what this day would be like, you know?
喔，我本来想像今天是怎样的一天
Emma laughing..
艾玛在笑
and everybody gathered around her cake, singing "Happy Birthday."
大家围绕著蛋糕唱“生日快乐”
And then we would all.. Hey, get out of the road, you stupid student driver!
然后--嘿，不要挡本姑娘的路 笨笨的初学者!!!
They have to learn.
他们总要学这点
- Hey. - What?
-嘿 -什么?
This is not bad.
这不错嘛
Oh, my God. Look, you made it into a bunny. How did you do that?
喔，天啊。你把它变成兔子了 你怎么弄的，罗斯?
Well, I just made these two things cheeks.
我把这边改成脸颊
And then I split this to make ears.
这部分再分两边，变成耳朵
Well, I am very impressed.
喔，我非常感动呢
Some can sing, some can dance.
有些人会唱歌，些人会跳舞
I, apparently, can turn phallic cakes into woodland creatures.
我显然 可以把“小弟弟”改成兔子蛋糕
Now, another way to organize your stuffed animals is by size.
还有另外一种方法来整理玩具 就是按照大小
I'm sorry, is this a game for Emma or for Monica?
对不起，这是给艾玛 玩的游戏，或是给莫妮卡?
Game?
游戏?
Emma, do you even know it's your birthday today? You're 1.
你知道今天是你生日吗? 你是一。
One year old. That's little.
就是一岁，这么小
That's my girl.
哈，这我的女儿??
That's how old you are.
这就是你的年龄
Did I teach her that? Did I just impart wisdom?
是我教她的吗? 或是我传授智能给她?
I want one.
喔，我也想要有一个
Me too.
我也是
There's no one around. Why don't we just take this one?
这里没人，干脆我们带走她，好吗?
- And head to Canada. - I was kidding.
-然后跑去加拿大? -我在开玩笑
I wasn't. Let's get going.
我可没有呢!! 快点出发吧
- Hey, are Ross and Rachel back? - No, not yet.
-嘿，罗斯和瑞秋回来了吗? -还没有呢
- Oh, good, I didn't miss the party. - What about your massage client?
-喔，好耶，我没错过派对嘛 -那你的按摩客户呢?
I just felt so bad missing this. So I just slipped him a little something, you know.
我觉得很内疚如果错过这派对 所以我给他一些东西
As long as I'm back in five or six hours, it'll be all right.
五或六个小时后再做也可以
Okay.
好！
If Ross and Rachel ask, I've been here the whole time. The whole time.
嘿，如果罗斯，瑞秋问起我， 说我一直待在这里
I've been here the whole time.
我一直待在这里的
Joey, we just saw you come in. You ran past us on the stairs.
乔伊，我们刚看到你进来 而且你跑上来时，在楼梯经过我们
I don't care that you left. I'm just glad that you're here. Thanks, you guys.
我不管你有没有离开 我很高兴你们现在在这里，谢谢大家
Hey, guys, come on. You gotta see what Emma just did.
嘿，大家过来 你们应该看看艾玛刚做了什么
- What? - Emma, how old are you?
- 什么? -艾玛，你几岁?
How old are you today?
你今天几岁?
Emma, that's right. You're that many.
对了， 艾玛就是一岁
Oh, my God, our daughter's a genius.
喔，天啊，我们女儿是一个天才
- This means.. - No! No science camp!
-这表示-- -不要有科学的说教了
Damn it! I'll put a candle on the cake.
喔，真是的，我把蜡烛放到蛋糕上
Oh, and, Emma, look at your stuffed animals lined up so neatly.
喔，艾玛，看看你的娃娃 排的如此整齐
Thanks.
谢谢
Okay, here we go.
好了，要开始了
Emma's first birthday cake.
这是艾玛第一个生日蛋糕
Go ahead, Emma, blow out the candle.
快吹啊，吹灭蜡烛
Come on, Emma. You can do it.
快，艾玛，你能做到的。
- What's wrong? Are you okay? - Oh, yeah, nothing.
-怎么啦，你还好吧? -喔，没事
These are happy tears.
这是快乐的眼泪
This is just what I wanted.
这就是我想要的
Hey, you made it into a bunny.
嘿，蛋糕已变成兔子形状的
What is wrong with me? It looked more delicious when it was a penis.
喔，我怎么啦， 为什么 “小弟弟”的形状时看来比较好吃
- Okay, you ready? - Yeah.
-好，准备好了吗? -是的
- And record. - Okay.
-那，开始录了 -好。
Big Brother audition. Take one.
试音.
I guess you could say I'm kind of a player.
我猜你会说 我是一个演员..
Okay. Let's..
好了.让我...
- Let's just try that again. - Okay.
- 我们再试一次. - 好的.
Hi, Emma. Well, your first birthday is over, and..
嗨，艾玛，你的生日刚结束了 而且--
Go! Go! Come on!
快啊，快啊
快啊，快点
Go! Go, Alan! Run, you hairy bastard!
熊熊，快跑啊 你这只笨熊